<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<LanguageData>

  <!-- natural -->

  <Heart.label>coração</Heart.label>
  <Heart.description>Fornece sangue e oxigênio para todas as partes do corpo. Pronto para encontrar um novo dono.</Heart.description>

  <Lung.label>pulmão</Lung.label>
  <Lung.description>Parte essencial do sistema respiratório.</Lung.description>

  <Kidney.label>rim</Kidney.label>
  <Kidney.description>Filtra e remove os resíduos do sangue.</Kidney.description>

  <Liver.label>fígado</Liver.label>
  <Liver.description>Desempenha um papel importante no metabolismo.</Liver.description>


  <!-- simple prosthetics (industrial tech) -->

  <SimpleProstheticLeg.label>perna protética simples</SimpleProstheticLeg.label>
  <SimpleProstheticLeg.description>Uma prótese simples feita para substituir uma perna perdida. Não é muito confortável, mas bastante eficiente.</SimpleProstheticLeg.description>

  <SimpleProstheticArm.label>braço protético simples</SimpleProstheticArm.label>
  <SimpleProstheticArm.description>Um simples, mas durável braço protético.</SimpleProstheticArm.description>

  <SimpleProstheticHeart.label>prosthetic heart</SimpleProstheticHeart.label>
  <SimpleProstheticHeart.description>A heart prosthesis. It contains an electric motor that pumps blood smoothly around the body. Users often report feeling tired, but it's better than the alternative.</SimpleProstheticHeart.description>

  <CochlearImplant.label>cochlear implant</CochlearImplant.label>
  <CochlearImplant.description>An implant which replaces normal hearing. An external microphone transmits a sound signal to electrodes wrapped around the inner ear's auditory sensing nerves. The electrodes stimulate the nerves according to the sound, creating a sensation of hearing. It's not as good as a natural ear, but it's a lot better than being deaf.</CochlearImplant.description>


  <!-- bionics (spacer tech) -->

  <BionicEye.label>olho biônico</BionicEye.label>
  <BionicEye.description>Uma peça de tecnologia avançada feita não só para substituir totalmente um olho natural, mas também para dar habilidades de visão sobrenatural.</BionicEye.description>

  <BionicArm.label>braço biônico</BionicArm.label>
  <BionicArm.description>Uma das próteses de braço mais sofisticada. Dá extrema força ao seu usuário.</BionicArm.description>

  <BionicLeg.label>perna biônica</BionicLeg.label>
  <BionicLeg.description>Uma perna biônica feita com a tecnologia de ponta para dar ao seu proprietário extremo conforto ao andar e força.</BionicLeg.description>

  <BionicSpine.label>bionic spine</BionicSpine.label>
  <BionicSpine.description>An advanced artificial spine. A biogel nerve bundle runs down an articulated plasteel core, surrounded by a lattice-dust healing system. It matches the performance of a biological spine.</BionicSpine.description>

  <BionicHeart.label>bionic heart</BionicHeart.label>
  <BionicHeart.description>An advanced artificial heart. It has synthetic muscle fibers for a realistic heartbeat, plus a high-flow pump for rapid circulation during high stress. It is better than a biological heart in almost every way.</BionicHeart.description>

  <BionicStomach.label>bionic stomach</BionicStomach.label>
  <BionicStomach.description>An advanced artificial stomach. A set of sensors and chemical synthesizers efficiently digest nearly any energy-bearing foodstuff. An integrated lattice-dust healing system automatically repairs any damage caused by the powerful acids. It is better than a biological stomach in almost every way.</BionicStomach.description>

  <BionicEar.label>bionic ear</BionicEar.label>
  <BionicEar.description>An advanced artificial ear implant. A collection of invisible subdermal microphones capture sound and transmit it to a biogel nerve interface that links directly with the auditory nerve. It's sensitive enough to hear a cat before you see it, can't be damaged by loud noise, and automatically tunes itself to pick out meaningful sounds in noisy environments.</BionicEar.description>


  <!-- bionic non-makeable -->

  <PowerClaw.label>garra potente</PowerClaw.label>
  <PowerClaw.description>Uma poderosa substituição para a mão que consiste em três garras mortais.</PowerClaw.description>


  <!-- archotech -->

  <ArchotechEye.label>archotech eye</ArchotechEye.label>
  <ArchotechEye.description>An artifical eye built by an archotech. It perceives every type of electromagnetic radiation, including radio waves, infrared, light, x-rays, and gamma rays. Its visual acuity is precise enough to read handwriting from twenty meters away. It can emit various wavelengths of radiation like a flashlight, and has an internal subpersona AI which helps highlight useful visual information. Externally, it looks like a natural human eye, except it can change color at will. Its internal workings are a mystery to all human minds.</ArchotechEye.description>

  <ArchotechArm.label>archotech arm</ArchotechArm.label>
  <ArchotechArm.description>An artifical arm built by an archotech. It's strong enough to crush a thick hardwood branch in its hand, and precise enough to write a sonnet on a grain of rice. It looks and feels like natural flesh, but it's harder to damage than plasteel. Even if it is harmed, it repairs itself over time. Its internal workings are a mystery to all human minds.</ArchotechArm.description>

  <ArchotechLeg.label>archotech leg</ArchotechLeg.label>
  <ArchotechLeg.description>An artifical leg built by an archotech. It looks and feels like natural flesh, but a pair of these can move the user as fast as a decent car, and it's harder to damage than plasteel. Even if it is harmed, it repairs itself over time. Its internal workings are a mystery to all human minds.</ArchotechLeg.description>


  <!-- artificial - simple prosthetics -->
  <!-- artificial - bionics -->
  <!--<ScytherBlade.label>lãmina de ceifeiro</ScytherBlade.label>-->
  <!--<ScytherBlade.description>Uma substituição para a mão com uma lâmina telescópica. Retirado a partir de ceifeiro mechanoide. Não é muito confortável, mas bastante eficaz como uma arma de curto alcance.</ScytherBlade.description>-->

</LanguageData>